RAHUL SAINI

ULUX DESIGNER & FRONTEND DEVELOPER



8882138706

saini14rahul@gmail.com

South Delhi, India

https://saini14rahul.github.io/Portfolio/

www.behance.net/rahulsaini51

SKILLS

- Design Thinking
- Visual Design
- Interaction Design
- Information Architecture
- Prototyping
- HTML
- CSS
- Responsive Design
- Basics of JavaScript
- Basics of React

TOOLS

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- Adobe Dreamweaver
- Notepad ++
- Visual Studio Code

EDUCATION

SECONDARY BOARD

N.I.O.S (National Institute Open of Schooling)

B.B.A (BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINSTRATION

M.D.U (Maharishi Dayanand University

PROFILE

Let me introduce myself, I'm a designer with a strong passion for design strategy. My Strength are my creativity, bringing ideas to the table and solving issues that a first seem impossible. I like the most in UI UX designer is collecting the information, researching, investigating and evaluating user requirements and then design the whatever user want.

EXPERIENCE

BOYINAWEB / DEC 2019 - FEB 2022

- Collaborated with senior team members to design and develop web interfaces and mobile applications.
- Contributed to project planning and feedback from senior designers and developers.
- Designed and created emailers, templates, and banners for marketing.
- Translated static UI designs into responsive, cross-browser-compatible HTML.

https://www.delhifurniture.com

https://www.gopalcorp.com

https://www.harpersbazaar.com

https://www.steelcase.com

ORBIT TECHSOL INDIA PVT. LTD. / MAR 2022 - DEC 2022

- Developed visually appealing and user-friendly web designs, ensuring alignment with modern UX/UI principles.
- Transformed static UI designs into fully functional, responsive with using HTML.
- Designed and implemented dashboards, newsletters, emailers, templates, and banners.
- Regularly updated and maintained the company website to ensure accurate, fresh, and engaging content while optimizing performance and usability.

VELOCIS SYSTEM PVT. LTD. / JAN 2023 - FEB 2024

- Designed and developed modern, user-friendly web interfaces and mobile applications.
- Collaborated with senior team members to compose and execute comprehensive project plans, ensuring timely and high-quality deliverables.